import { Question } from './types';

export const quizData3: Question[] = [
  {
    id: 1,
    question: "What was the name of Bob Marley's backing band?",
    options: ["The Singers", "The Wailers", "The Chanters", "The Crooners"],
    correctAnswer: 1,
    category: "Music"
  },
  {
    id: 2,
    question: "In computing, which port is generally used for HTTP connections?",
    options: ["80", "120", "10", "50"],
    correctAnswer: 0,
    category: "Technology"
  },
  {
    id: 3,
    question: "On Ordinance Survey maps, a blue triangle denotes what?",
    options: ["Pub", "Triangulation Point", "Youth Hostel", "Bus Stop"],
    correctAnswer: 1,
    category: "Art"
  },
  {
    id: 4,
    question: "Which instrument is commonly used in Scottish folk music",
    options: ["Banjo", "Bagpipes", "Accordion", "Sitar"],
    correctAnswer: 1,
    category: "Music"
  },
  {
    id: 5,
    question: "Who wrote the 1897 novel The War of the Worlds?",
    options: ["Joseph Conrad", "Charles Dickens", "HG Wells", "William Morris"],
    correctAnswer: 2,
    category: "Literature"
  },
  {
    id: 6,
    question: "What animal does the adjective Bovine refer to?",
    options: ["Dog", "Cow", "Pig", "Cat"],
    correctAnswer: 1,
    category: "Animals"
  },
  {
    id: 7,
    question: "In which country was the 1970 football World Cup held?",
    options: ["Mexico", "West Germany", "Spain", "Argentina"],
    correctAnswer: 0,
    category: "Sports"
  },
  {
    id: 8,
    question: "Which song starts 'Big wheels keep on turning'?",
    options: ["Midnight Train to Georgia", "Dani California", "Sweet Home Alabama", "Hotel California"],
    correctAnswer: 2,
    category: "Music"
  },
  {
    id: 9,
    question: "In US politics, for what does the P in POTUS stand?",
    options: ["President", "Place", "Pennsylvania", "Post"],
    correctAnswer: 0 ,
    category: "Geography"
  },
  {
    id: 10,
    question: "Who released the 1977 song You Took The Words Right Out of My Mouth?",
    options: ["Prince", "Elton John", "Rick Astley", "Meatloaf "],
    correctAnswer: 3,
    category: "Music"
  },
  {
    id: 11,
    question: "Can you tell me which song by The Doors features the phrase 'We want the world and we want it now'?",
    options: ["When the Music’s Over", "People Are Strange", "Moonlight Drive", "You're Lost Little Girl"],
    correctAnswer: 0,
    category: "Music"
  },
  {
    id: 12,
    question: "Which guitarist is famous for playing a Fender Stratocaster upside down?",
    options: ["Eric Clapton", " Jimi Hendrix", "Jimmy Page", "Pete Townshend"],
    correctAnswer: 1,
    category: "Music"
  },
  {
    id: 13,
    question: "What is the origin of the word “salary”?",
    options: ["Latin", "Greek", "French", "Arabic"],
    correctAnswer: 0,
    category: "History"
  },
  {
    id: 14,
    question: "Which language does the word “robot” come from?",
    options: ["Russian", "Czech", "German", "Japanese"],
    correctAnswer: 1,
    category: "History"
  },
  {
    id: 15,
    question: "What does the word “quarantine” originally mean?",
    options: ["Isolation", "Forty days", "Disease control", "Ship inspection"],
    correctAnswer: 1,
    category: "History"
  },
  {
    id: 16,
    question: "The word “candidate” comes from Latin and originally referred to someone who was:",
    options: ["Chosen by gods", "Wearing white", "From noble birth", "A warrior"],
    correctAnswer: 1,
    category: "History"
  },
  {
    id: 17,
    question: " Which word comes from the name of a Roman god of doorways and transitions?",
    options: ["January", "Portal", "Exit", "Passage"],
    correctAnswer: 0,
    category: "History"
  },
  {
    id: 18,
    question: "The word “nightmare” originally referred to:",
    options: ["A scary dream", "A demon sitting on your chest", "A ghost", "A sleep disorder"],
    correctAnswer: 1,
    category: "History"
  },
  {
    id: 19,
    question: "The word “trivia” comes from Latin and originally meant:?",
    options: ["Useless facts", "Three roads", "Small talk", "Public knowledge"],
    correctAnswer: 2,
    category: "History"
  },
  {
    id: 20,
    question: "What is the origin of the word “pandemic”?",
    options: ["Greek", "Latin", "Sanskrit", "French"],
    correctAnswer: 0,
    category: "History"
  }
];
